In this video, we'll look at the third commonly used scoring method.
在这个视频中 我们将了解第三个常见评分方法
It's called concat, and the way to do it is to use a feedforward neural network.
称为 Concat 计算原理是使用前馈神经网络
To take a simple example,
举个简单的例子
let's say we're scoring this encoder hidden state,
假设我们要对这个编码器隐藏状态评分
at the fourth time step at the decoder.
位于解码器的第四个时间步
Again this is an oversimplified example scoring only one,
同样 这是一个过度简化的示例 只评分一次
while in practice we'll actually do a matrix and do it all discord in one step.
在实际操作中 我们将计算一个矩阵 在一个时间步对所有项评分
The concat scoring method,
Concat 评分方法的常见执行方式是
is commonly done by concatenating the two vectors,
将这两个向量相连
and making that the input to a feed forward neural network.
并将结果作为前馈神经网络的输入
Let's see how that works. So, we merge them,
我们来看看原理 合并这两个向量
we concat them into one vector,
连接成一个向量
and then we pass them through a neural network.
然后传入神经网络中
This network has a single hidden layer,
这个网络有一个隐藏图层
and outputs this score.
输出这个得分
The parameters of this network,
这个网络的参数
are learned during the training process.
是在训练流程中学习的
Namely the WA weights matrix,
即 Wa 权重矩阵
and the VA weights matrix.
和 Va 权重矩阵
To look at how the calculation is done,
我们来看看计算方式
this is our concatenated vector,
这是连接后的向量
we simply multiply it by W of A,
将其乘以 Wa
we apply 10H activation producing this two by one matrix.
应用双曲正切激活函数 生成这个 2X1 矩阵
We multiply that by the V of A weights matrix,
将该矩阵乘以 Va 权重矩阵
and we get the score for this encoder hidden state.
得出这个编码器隐藏状态的得分
Formally, it is expressed like this,
正式公式是这样的
where H of T as we've mentioned is the hidden state at the current time step,
正如之前提到的 ht 是当前时间步的隐藏状态
and H of S is the collection of the set of encoder hidden states.
hs 是编码器隐藏状态的集合
This is the concatenation and then we multiply it by W of A,
这是向量连接部分 将其乘以 Wa
tan H activation and then multiply it by V of A transpose.
应用双曲正切激活函数 然后乘以 Va 转置矩阵
One thing to note is the difference.
要注意一个差别
So concat is very similar to the scoring method from Mark Daniel paper,
Concat 与 Bahdanau 论文中的评分方法非常相似
but this is the one,
这是来自
this is the concat method from the Lung paper,
Luong 论文中的 Concat 方法
where there's only one weight matrix.
其中只有一个权重矩阵
In the Mark Daniel paper there are two major differences that we can look at.
在 Bahdanau 论文中 有两个不同之处
One of them is that the weights matrix is split into two,
一个不同之处是权重矩阵拆分成了两个
so we don't have just W of A,
不仅有 Wa
we have W of A and U of A,
还有 Ua
and each is applied to the respective vector.
每个都应用到相应的向量上
The decoder hidden state in this case,
即这里的解码器隐藏状态
and the encoder hidden state at this case.
和这里的编码器隐藏状态
Another thing to note is that the Mark Daniel paper used
另一个不同之处是 Bahdanau 论文
the hidden state from the previous time step at the decoder.
使用了解码器上个时间步的隐藏状态
While in the loop paper it uses the one from the current time step at the decoder.
而 Luong 论文使用的是解码器当前时间步的隐藏状态
Let's make a note on notation here,
对于这里的记法 有个注意事项
in case you're planning to read the papers.
以防你要阅读论文
Here we've used the notation mainly from the Lung paper where
我们主要使用的是 Luong 论文中的记法
we referred to the encoder and the decoder hidden states as H. So,
将编码器和解码器的隐藏状态称为 h
H of T for the decoder,
ht 表示解码器
and H of S for the encoder.
hs 表示编码器
This means so H is for hidden state,T is for target,
h 表示隐藏状态 t 表示目标
so that's the target sequence that we're going to
也就是我们要输出的目标序列
output so that's associated with the decoder.
与解码器相关
S is for source.
s 表示来源
In the Mark Daniel paper,
在 Bahdanau 论文中
this is called S. So,
这个称为 s
it is not H, it's called S. So,
它不是 h 而是 s
now the picture is complete.
整个流程就讲完了
Now, we've gone over the entire attention process.
我们介绍了整个注意力流程
It's time now to look at some applications in the next video.
在下个视频中 我们将查看一些应用